Siddharth Joshi . Jarvis Consulting

Heya! I am Siddharth Joshi. I am a Software Engineer with Bachelors of Technology in Computer Engineering. I have a passion for software engineering as I believe technology has revolutionized the entire world by coming up with meaningful solutions and delivering values. Breaking down problems is something I enjoy. This is the exact thing which motivates me and exictes me is that I get to craft solutions to real world problems collaborating with other like-minded individuals towards the same goal. I have worked with wide array of technologies from Java and Spring Boot to Python and Django along with Data Engineering. I am confident I can bring values along with my technical acumen to your organization.

Skills

Proficient: Java, Linux/Bash, RDBMS/SQL, Agile/Scrum, Git, Python Competent: JavaScript, C/C++, Django, Flask, Godot Game Engine Familiar: C#, .NET Framework, Amazon Web Services, NoSQL, Docker

Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis data eng SiddharthJoshi

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: A Monitoring Agent intended for the Jarvis Linux Cluster Administrator Team (LCA). This project gathers the real-time data from all the available machines such as hardware specifications (CPU, Memory, etc.). This data is persisted in a relational database providing accurate records of data at a particular timestamp. This data will be used by the LCA team to manage resources. This project can be deployed across multiple host machines to enable real time data gathering. The technologies used for this project are Postgres Database, Docker, Git, GitHub and Linux.

Core Java Apps [GitHub]:

- Twitter App: Curabitur laoreet tristique leo, eget suscipit nisi. Sed in sodales ex. Maecenas vitae tincidunt dui, et eleifend quam.
- JDBC App: Curabitur laoreet tristique leo, eget suscipit nisi. Sed in sodales ex. Maecenas vitae tincidunt dui, et eleifend quam.
- Grep App: Curabitur laoreet tristique leo, eget suscipit nisi. Sed in sodales ex. Maecenas vitae tincidunt dui, et eleifend quam.

Springboot App [GitHub]: Not Started

Python Data Analytics [GitHub]: Not Started

Hadoop [GitHub]: Not Started
Spark [GitHub]: Not Started

Cloud/DevOps [GitHub]: Not Started

Highlighted Projects

Cheap Flight Finder [GitHub]: This Project Prototype is designed for people who want real time updates of price drop in flight tickets. This Project sends real time alerts via email whenever flights prices are low.

Blood Bank Data Management System: A full stack application for the university hospital utilizing HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, MySQL and PHP. Enhanced the older donor management system of the hospital by equipping the blood donation department with the latest cutting-edge technologies.

Professional Experiences

Software Engineer, Jarvis (Nov 2023 - Present): Leveraged multiple cutting-edge technologies to build multiple projects spanning in various fields of software.

Software Engineer, ABXR Engine (Aug 2023 - Dec 2023): Designed and Implemented RESTful APIs for AI-based text-to-voice generation, enabling the users to choose from a variety of celebrity voices resulting in enhanced user experience and engagement.

Education

Charotar University of Science and Technology (2018-2022), Bachelor of Technology, U & P U Patel Department of Computer Engineering - GPA: 3.5/4.0

Miscellaneous

- Getting Started with Cloud for the Enterprise
- Getting Started with Enterprise Data Science
- Swimming
- Hiking
- Volunteer, Charusat University: Volunteered for providing basic necessities to people in rural areas.